brian.d.pemberton@gmail.com

Pemby.github.io

linkedin.com/in/brpemberton/

Brian Pemberton

SKILLS

I am a technical support professional with a tenacity to solve problems using technology and automation. I have demonstrated a history of working in the primary/secondary education industry. I am skilled in hardware and software repair, system administration and computer programming. I am experienced in setting up development environments, network stacks, web servers, MDM server-client configurations. I have development experience using OOP and MVC paradigms with the following software frameworks: JavaFX, Django, and .NET.

EXPERIENCE

Portland Public Schools, Portland OR — Instructional Technology Assistant

Fe2014 - PRESENT

- Troubleshoot, diagnose, repair computer hardware, software, networks, and peripheral equipment.
- Technical support to staff, students, and community members via telephone, virtually, remote and in-person.
- Audio Visual support and for live performances and events. Micing, mixing, lighting, soundboards, and post-production.
- Supervised, trained, and managed student-run technology support teams that focused on tech support and technology projects.
- Supervised a computer lab of students before, during, and after school, emphasizing exploring and experimenting with computers and technology.
- Maintain positive relationships with staff, students, and community members and keep open office hours for technical support meetings.

The Mac Store, Portland OR - Macologist

June 2006 - Dec 2014

- I streamlined help desk processes by creating scripts and software for repeated procedures.
- Helped formulate the help desk processes by coaching my team to use note templates that focused on consistency and including all relevant information.
- Specialized software imaging deployments and in logical data recovery.
- I was consistently able to fix complex problems and mend relationships with people and their technology.

Apple Inc, Santa Clara, & New York, NY- Genius

June 2006 - May 2009

- Work with a full spectrum of customers, from brand new users to Apple professional customers.
- Responsible for constant changes in technical knowledge.
- Multi-tasking under a tight appointment system.
- Working with a team and daily practice of fine tuning empathy skills, patience, and listening.
- Aligning with customer concerns while offering non-intrusive solutions.
- Setting clear expectations about service outcomes.
- Documenting all service related steps in a CRM-Ticketing software

EDUCATION

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City UT — Bachelor of Science — Computer Science

2018 - 2020

Portland Community College, Portland OR — Associate of Applied Science - Computer Information Systems

2014 - 2016

Certifications

CompTIA - Project+ Certification

2020

Portland Community College — *Linux Server Administration* 2016

Apple — Certified Macintosh Technician (ACMT) Certification 2007-2013

Digidesign - Certified Pro Tools Operator 2005